Bitcoin is going to eclipse, get over
$200,000 by the end of the year. What do
we have to see? Like, is there a sign
that we have to see for all that to
happen? If those three things happen, I
think the $200,000 target is a lot.
Every sign that I see suggests that ETFs
are buying, corporations are buying, and
governments are buying. You're going to
see 10, maybe more governments around
the world make their first allocation to
Bitcoin this year. It's happening.
People aren't talking about it that
much, but it's happening. I think there
could be a DeFi boom at the end of this
year. What is going to happen once we
have a recession?
A lot of volatility in crypto and risk
assets right now. We're talking about
the future of prices and the markets for
uh investors. For the next guest, Matt
Hogan, CIO of Bitwise. I'm Dave Lynn.
Bonnie Tay, Bonnie Blockchain. Thanks
for joining us, Matt. Good to see you.
Thanks for having me. I'm excited to be
here. Let's just get straight to it.
Bitcoin, what's what's happening with
the price currently? What's going to
happen to the price in the next nine
months? Yeah, our prediction is that
Bitcoin is going to eclipse get over
$200,000 by the end of the year. What's
happening right now is you have a huge
amount of good news in Bitcoin. You have
a US strategic reserve where the
government now owns Bitcoin. You have
improvements on the regulatory front.
You have institutional adoption. You may
be wondering why aren't prices higher?
The reason is we've had a bunch of
economic uncertainty that's caused not
just Bitcoin but all risky assets to
fall. Stocks are down substantially. So
the market has dipped. But I think over
time as that economic volat volatility
subsides, you're going to see all that
good news catch up to Bitcoin and it's
going to propel it to new all-time highs
and indeed above $200,000 for the year.
What do we have to see? Like is there a
sign that we have to see for all that to
happen? Yeah, there are two things to
keep your eye on. So, one, Bitcoin's
price is set by supply and demand. And
we all know the supply, right? There'll
only be 21 million. We only make 165,000
new ones a year. So, you have to watch
the demand. The three things to watch
are ETFs gaining inflows. Are
corporations like Micro Strategy and
Metanet continuing to buy Bitcoin? And
are governments buying Bitcoin? If those
three things happen, I think the
$200,000 target is a lock. So, I would
keep your eye on that. It would help. If
the economy improves, if we don't enter
a recession, that would help. But it's
really about does the demand materialize
in the way I think it will. Every sign
that I see suggests that ETFs are
buying, corporations are buying, and
governments are buying. That's why I'm
so bullish, but they have to keep buying
in order for us to get to that $200,000
target. You said they keep on buying. At
what scale are you talking about? Yeah.
So, last year ETFs bought half a million
Bitcoin. Again, remember the Bitcoin
network only produced 165,000 Bitcoin.
So, it bought three times the total
supply. Corporations bought 250,000
Bitcoin. Governments, I think this year,
could buy a couple hundred thousand
Bitcoin. So, I think if you look at
those three sources, I think they'll buy
more than a million Bitcoin this year.
And where is it going to come from? The
only place it can come from is people
who already hold Bitcoin. The only way
they will sell is if the price goes up.
That's why I'm so bullish on the market.
So, government, which which branch of
the government? Look, the US already
established a strategic Bitcoin reserve,
right? It already holds $17 billion in
Bitcoin. And the executive order from
President Trump told the Secretary of
Commerce and the Secretary of Treasury
to figure out ways to acquire more
Bitcoin without impacting taxholder. How
could they do that? They could sell some
of the gold that the US has. They could
sell other crypto assets that the US has
and plow that into Bitcoin. I think
we're going to see that happen this
year. I think the US is going to
increase. And not just the US. We found
out that Abu Dhabi bought half a billion
dollars of Bitcoin. We've gotten calls
from multiple other governments that are
investigating Bitcoin. I think you're
going to see 10, maybe more governments
around the world make their first
allocation to Bitcoin this year. It's
happening. People aren't talking about
it that much, but it's happening and
it's a very big deal. I want to get your
comment on the crypto stockpile. Why do
you think they pick Salana, Ethereum,
Cardano, and XRP? Yeah, you know, first
it's important to remember that there's
a difference between the strategic
reserve, which is Bitcoin only, and this
crypto asset stockpile. My base case is
that they looked at the market and they
took the largest assets, right? Those
are essentially the largest assets
excluding a few assets, excluding
Binancecoin, excluding Tron. So, Doge,
excluding Doge. Yes, they didn't want
Doge, but it's the it's maybe the
largest sort of US- ccentric
blockchains. I don't think there's more
to it than that, but I think the
strategic reserve is the big deal. The
stockpile is just going to hold those
assets. The strategic reserve, I think,
is going to go out into the market and
end up acquiring more Bitcoin. I think
that's a very big deal.
What is going to happen once we have a
recession? M recessions negatively
impact all risk assets until the
government decides to provide economic
support. So Bitcoin is a risk asset. It
is a risk asset in the short term. So if
we if we look like we're driving into a
recession and the government doesn't
look like it's going to lower interest
rates or provide quantitative easing or
fiscal support, that will be negative
for Bitcoin. That could send us back to
the $72,000 level. It could send us
potentially below that. But my guess is
that governments will come in and
support the economy. I think we've made
it very difficult to have a real
recession. I know we're talking tough in
the US, but I think the government will
ultimately blink. I think you'll see
that in Europe. You're already seeing
Germany doing that. I think you'll see
that in parts of Asia. You're seeing
economic stimulus in China right now. I
think that's going to grow. So
ultimately, I think we'll blink before
we get a big recession. But if we do
enter a severe recession, my $200,000
target probably won't happen. That would
be challenging for Bitcoin. XRP, you
filed for an XRP ETF, but let's say for
the crypto community, it's not
considered the sexy bet, right? I want
to know your thought. Why XRP? And maybe
just a low forecast. Yeah, sure. The way
I think about XRP is it's proven a few
things. It's a blockchain that's worked
for a very long period of time. It's
extremely low cost to operate. It
processes high amounts of transaction
volume at very low cost and has a strong
community. The problem with XRP is it
hasn't developed its primary use cases.
It was designed to be a B2B blockchain,
right? Businessto business transactions,
international payments. That really
hasn't materialized. I would argue the
reason it hasn't materialized is it
faced a major lawsuit from the SEC,
existential regulatory threat, and now
we get to see what it can do. There's no
guarantee that it succeeds. I think it's
entirely possible that you we come back
and do an interview in 2 years and
nothing happened on XRP, the ETF didn't
gather assets, and the asset is down.
But I think what the crypto community
misses is it's also possible that now
that they're able to try to execute on
their strategy that they in fact succeed
and you're seeing significant
technological progress on the XRP
ledger. So I would say it's it's a
divisive coin for a reason which is
there worlds where it amounts to nothing
and worlds where it's very successful.
We'll see which world materializes in
the next few years. But people who
guarantee it will be a huge success are
wrong. And people who guarantee it will
go to zero are also wrong. We think it's
it's in the middle. I'm going to send
you a calendar invite. We'll interview
you in two years. There you go. I'm in.
Two-year followup. Just on the followup
to Bonnie's question. So tell us a bit
more about this ETF. Actively managed,
passively managed. How does it work?
Yeah. So, we can't talk much about the
ETP beyond what's in the filing, but
what's in the filing is it's an ETP that
will hold XRP in cold storage. It's
passively managed. It's just an exposure
vehicle. Some people can buy crypto
directly. That's great. We love it.
Particularly people who self-custody. We
think that's fantastic. Other people
need an ETP. And so, we designed these
rappers to make it easy for traditional
investors to access the space. Are
people asking for it? Yeah. Again, yes,
absolutely. I know in crypto it's a
divisive market, but the thing about
divisive market is there are cadres of
fans. There are people who want an XRP
ETF. Absolutely. There are people who
wouldn't touch it with a 10-ft pole, and
there are people who will embrace it
like it was, you know, a teddy bear. Um,
and uh, I think both of those will exist
in the market.
Uh, speaking of ETFs, there's a growing
debate as to whether or not actively
managed ETFs or passively managed ETFs
will become more dominant in the future.
I'm not talking about specifically
XRP, you know, ETPs or just crypto ETFs,
ETFs overall. What's your view point?
So, I am an index-based investor. My
core view is that the thing I'm most
confident about in crypto more than
anything else is that crypto, the
industry will be much more important in
the future than it is today. That this
will be a 10, 20, 30 trillion market.
That's what I feel the most. If that's
what you're confident about, just buy an
index fund because you're going to get
that 10x appreciation. You won't have to
pick and choose assets. I think active
will have a place too because it's
definitely an inefficient market and
they're very smart managers who can pick
and choose assets. Those managers just
aren't me. So, for my bet, index-based
investing is the right bet for most
people. But for sure, there's going to
be a vibrant active market and we know
some great active managers out there.
There's space for both to exist.
memecoin ETFs
basically. No. Uh, look, look, I
actually have a I I I have a warm place
in my heart for uh for Doge, the
original me the problem with meme coins,
there two. They come and go. They're
ephemeral, and then they're controlled
by insiders who rug people. Most meme
coins you should avoid, you know, like
the plague. Dogecoin has been around for
a while and uh there are no insiders so
it's fine but it you know it's not the
future of finance. The future of finance
is being built on Bitcoin, Ethereum,
Salana and a few other assets. Those are
the serious assets. People could
speculate on certain meme coins but it's
mostly not for me. Yeah. I'm just going
back to the markets for a minute. Why is
Bitcoin still treating or being treated
as a leverage play on the NASDAQ? In
other words, going into the future,
what's going to cause a divergence
between Bitcoin and traditional
equities? Yeah. So, so interesting you
ask. Here's what we see in the data.
What we see in the data is that when
there's a challenging movement for like
the NASDAQ, Bitcoin dips and then rips.
What do I mean by that? If you look at
all the days where the S&P 500 is down
2% or more over the last decade, Bitcoin
on average is down 2.6% on those days.
So, it's actually worse than just
holding stocks. But if you fast forward
a year from there, it's up 190% on
average. So I think what happens is it's
again a risk asset. When the market goes
risk off, you increase your discount
factor on risk assets. And the more
volatile they are, the harder they fall.
But the long-term tailwind is so strong
that they pick back up. I actually look
at those dips like the one we've seen
this year, which you mentioned at the
top. I think a phenomenal opportunity
because from my view the long-term
output for where Bitcoin is going is
better today than it was 6 months ago
and better than it was 2 years ago. And
if that's the case, this pullback is
just a discount. Bitcoin's on sale.
That's what I think is true. So, you're
buying the dip? I am buying the dip.
Absolutely. But only Bitcoin, though.
Well, yes. I think Bitcoin has the
cleanest case right now. I I'm, you
know, look, I'm very optimistic on
Ethereum. I'm very optimistic on Salana,
but I think they have more sort of wood
to chop, work to do before they get out
of their existential struggles. You have
to see regulation pass. You have to see
institutional DeFi. You have to see
greater adoption. It's probably a great
contrarian bet. If you're a long-term
investor, this is a great time to access
uh Ethereum or Salana. If you're a
short-term investor, I think there could
be volatility ahead. Bitcoin, I think,
has clear sailing. Some of the DeFi
assets I think have clear sailing. Those
layer ones in the middle I think could
face you know more months of churn. You
said DeFi products. What are we talking
about? Yeah. So if you look at if you
look at things like unis swap or uh
finance or
a activity on those is at all-time highs
and they've proven themselves through
multiple volatile markets and the
regulation is improving significantly.
And so I think we're going to see people
realize that those are already at
all-time highs. We're just not thinking
about them. So as excited as we were
about DeFi in 2021 and the DeFi summer,
we were all thinking about those assets.
People have sort of forgotten about
them. But behind the scenes, their
business is better than ever and it's
actually growing really fast and they
actually benefit from the huge
regulatory shift in Washington. I think
there could be a DeFi boom at the end of
this year. So if I were looking for sort
of the safe play in crypto, I would look
at Bitcoin. If I were looking for
underloved assets that could really be
revalued, I would look all the way down
to things like Uniswap and A. I think
there's a real opportunity there. Like
the OG DeFi coins. Yes, absolutely. The
OG DeFi coins. That's going to come from
the retail side with the institutional
side. You think? Well, I think a little
bit of both. First retail, then
institutional. I do think institutions
are waking up to the fact that DeFi is a
real thing and not going away. And I
think Wall Street's going to start
building on DeFi. So, I think there'll
be an institutional play, but retail
will be first. Retail are the people who
know those protocols and are using those
protocols. And I think we'll start to
look at the TVL and the trading activity
and be like, "Wow, we're at all-time
highs. ETH's not at an all-time high,
but the activity on a is maybe I should
think about that as an investment
vehicle as well." If you could go back
to your younger self and just give
yourself a piece of investment advice,
what would it be? Yeah, buy Bitcoin,
right? Come on. We all should have done
that. Um, you know, look, the the the
the thing that we've experienced in
crypto is the most important thing is to
stay allocated, right? That would be the
advice. Don't put in so much that you're
going to panic if it pulls back because
volatility is part of the game. Uh, you
know, I've been at Bitwise now for seven
years, have lived through multiple 70%
draw downs. You have to be willing to
sustain those and as we mentioned
earlier, buy the dip if you can. Um,
that's really the key. But sure, if I
could tell my, you know, 10 year old
self to do something, it would be to buy
a lot of Bitcoin and not think about it
for 10 years. What would you tell your
22-year-old self? Oh, man. I would start
saving up money and then buy Bitcoin.
I like this guy.
What's next for Bitwise? Yeah. So,
Bitwise, you know, we're a crypto asset
manager. We'll continue to launch new
exchange traded funds and new exchange
traded products. We've also started
moving into the onchain solution space.
So, we're now a major player in the
staking market. We think again crypto is
going to be 10x bigger than it is today
and the world is going to want a
cryptospecific asset manager. So, I'm
always thinking about new products and
then I'm always out there on the road
talking to people about the
opportunities in Bitcoin, in DeFi, just
like what we're doing today. Well, I'm
sure the audience will learn a lot. Any
uh last questions from you, Bonnie? Come
to Asia.
I would love to. It's it's it's very
much on our radar. It's a very exciting
market. There's this huge amount going
on in many ways, steps ahead of where we
are in the US. So, um I will I will all
right and chat in two years, huh? That's
right. And that's already calendar
invites. It's it's in the phone. Bonnie
and I will see you there. Thanks so
much. Appreciate it. Thank you.